ATHM Textile Industry Stereographs 6524/006 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ATHM Textile Industry Stereographs
1842-2003
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
6524/006 P
6.33 cubic feet
6.3 linear ft.
Photographs, postcards, stereographs.
Stereoscopic photographs and postcards show the exteriors, interiors, machinery, and workers of textile mills. Also showing the processes in making textiles from raw fibers.
10232490
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, March 15, 2018
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 28, 2018
Scope and Contents
This collection is divided into three series:
I: Images of Mills, Alphabetical by Location. Consists entirely of stereoscopic images arranged alphabetically by state, then by ciy/town. Most of the images are of mills, both interior and exterior views. Also includes views from around the mill towns.
II: General Images Organized by Textile Related Subject. Consists of a mix of about 40% stereoscopic images and 60% postcards. These images are arranged by subject based on ATHM numerically coded "TT" local subject headings. The subject headings have been kept, but the "TT" codings have been dropped. Most of the images depict the production of cotton and wool, though there is a section on flax and other fibers. Subjects include both fiber production, growing wool and cotton, and processing into cloth.
III: Pacific Mills Images Organized by Textile Related Subject. Consists entirely of stereoscopic images arranged by subject, the same as Series II. The images depict the production of cotton and wool textiles, with subjects focusing on the production of cloth.
A stereoscopic viewer is included in the collection in order to view the stereoscopic images in 3D.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6524/001: ATHM Textile Industry Documents 6524/002 P: ATHM Textile Industry Photographs 6524/003 MB: ATHM Textile Industry Cloth Labels 6524/004 G: ATHM Textile Industry Graphics 6524/005 P: ATHM Textile Industry Postcards 6524/007 MB: ATHM Textile Industry Memorabilia 6524/008 LS: ATHM Textile Industry Glass Lantern Slides 6524/009 F: ATHM Textile Industry Film 6524/010 AV: ATHM Textile Industry Audio-Visual Materials 6524/011 PUBS: ATHM Textile Industry Publications 6524/012 mf: ATHM Textile Industry Publications on Microfilm 6524/013 PUBS: ATHM Textile Industry Auction Catalog Collection 6524/014 OH: ATHM Textile Industry Oral History
Arrangement
Series I: Images of Mills, Alphabetical by Location
Series II: General Images Organized by Textile Related Subject
Series III: Pacific Mills Images Organized by Textile Related Subject
Textile workers; Textile industry; Textile machinery; Pacific Mills
10232490
- Series I: Images of Mills, Alphabetical by Location
  Scope and Contents
  Stereoscopic images organized alphabetically by state, then by city/town.
  - Connecticut (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Item 1: No. 2 Mill, Grosvenordale, Conn. (Lower Village) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. View of Canal and mill beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
      Format: Stereoptic print.
    - Item 2: Cotton House, North Grosvenordale, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. Written on reverse in pencil, "Cotton House and three rowes North Grosvenordale, CT." 18 x 10 cm.
    - Item 3: Rockville Mill, Race Overflow, A.Rockville, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. No. 17 in the Rhode Island Series, Hopkinton and Westerly. Published by O. Langworthy & Co., Ashaway, R.I. Photographed by C. Seaver, Jr. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Dart's Mill, Rockville, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Dart's Mill, Rockville, Conn. n.d. F.E. North noted on front left side bar. Stone Mill and Belding Mill. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Front Taft Mill, Taftville, Conn., 1871 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      No. 137 in the series Norwich and Vicinity, Webster's Photogrpahic Studio, Norwich conn. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 6: Heminway & Bartlett Silk Co., Watertown, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. Valley and white buildings, pond to left. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 7: Willimantic Linen Co's Thread Works, Willimantic, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. Prescott & White, Photographers, Hartford, Conn. Railroad tracks over river, town and Linen Co. beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 8: Willimantic Linen Co's Threadworks, Willimantic, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. Prescott & White, Photographers, Hartford, Conn. View of two men under bridge. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 9: Willimantic Linen Co's Threadworks, Willimantic, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. Prescott & White, Photographers, Hartford, Conn. View of dam. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 10: Willimantic Linen Co's Thread Works, Willimantic, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      n.d. Prescott & White, Photographers, Hartford, Conn. View of gate house. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 11: Willimantic Linen Company's Thread Works (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Willimantic, Conn.
    - Item 12: Willimantic Linen Company's Thread Works (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Item 13: Willimantic Linen Company and Dam (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Item 17: Willimantic Linen Company Housing (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Georgia (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Item 1: Augusta Factory, Augusta, Geo. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      n.d. Photographed by John Usher, Jr. Grounds, housing and mill beyond. 17.5 x 10 cm.
  - Maine (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Item 1: Barker Mill, Auburn, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. No 9. in The Latest Series, Views of Lewiston and Auburn. View of front of mill. 18 x 11 cm.
    - Item 2: Laconia Mill, Biddeford, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. River in foreground, mill buildings beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 3: Panoramic view, falls & factory, Brunswick, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Panoramic view, falls & factory, Brunswick, Me. n.d. No. 26 in the series Geo. W. Barnes' Views of Brunswick and Topsham. Cabot Mill, cotton factory from Topsham side of river. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: View of cotton factory from Topsham side, Brunswick, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      View of cotton factory (Cabot Mill) from Topsham side, Brunswick, Me. n.d. Local Views published for B.G. Dennison, Brunswick, Me. by Miller & Best, Boston. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Cotton Factory from Little Bridge, Topsham, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Cotton Factory from Little Bridge, Topsham, Me. n.d. Local Views published for B.G. Dennison, Brunswick, Me. by Miller & Best, Boston. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 6: Camden Woolen Factory, Camden, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Black-and-white image of three-story building with square tower topped with cupola; two-story addition on the left with a one-story, shed-like structure in front. Smokestack lies between the shed and the two-story addition. Image is faded so difficult to see, but there are people in the windows, standing on the roof of the shed, and standing on the roof of the extension in front of the tower (one woman can be seen standing there). Photographed by H. A. Mills. ca. 1887-1890. 17.25 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 7: Exterior view of Androscoggin Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. No 5 A. in the State of Maine series, Lewiston and Neighborhood. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 8: Androscoggin Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Exterior view of Androscoggin "A" Mills, Lewiston, Me. n.d. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 9: Androscoggin Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. No. 187 in the series, Lewiston and Vicinity, Series B. Published by Conant Bros., Pilsbury Block, Lewiston, Me. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 10: Lewiston Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Bates Mfg. Co., canal and mill. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 11: Bates Yard, Bates Mfg. Co., Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 12: Bates Manufacturing Company, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Douglass & Cook, Stationers and Dealers in Pictures, Frames, &c., Lewiston, Me. ca. 1880-1900. #16 in Lewiston, Maine, First Series: Hill, Bates and Continental Mills. Exterior view of Bates and Continental Mills, with surrounding buildings. Image taken from a high point (rooftop or hill). 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 13: Continental Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. American Views, Standard Series. View of mills from across the river. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 14: Continental Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      State of Maine, Lewiston and neighborhood
    - Item 15: Continental Mill, Lewiston, ME (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Item 16: Continental Mills, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. American Views, Standard Series. View of mills from across the river. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 17: Continental Mill-yard (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Possibly Continental Mills, Lewiston, Maine. ca. 1900. View of mill buildings, grounds. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 18: General View, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 19: Lewiston Canal from Androscoggin Mills (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Lewiston, Maine second series. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 20: Work on L.A.W. Co. Canal, Lewiston, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Auburn and Vicinity, Series C. Published by Conant Bros. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 21: Farwell Mills, Lisbon, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Exterior of mills. Published by J.C. Higgins, Bath, ME. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 22: Worumbo Factory, Lisbon Falls, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Sawyer, S. W., photographer and publisher of stereoscopic and other views. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 23: Skowhegan Woolen Factory, Skowhegan, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Kennebec Valley Views, photographed and published by S.S. Vose. View of mills from across river. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 24: South Windham Mfg. Co., Windham, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Written on reverse in pencil, "Back of mill with the boardinghouse in the distance." 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 25: Windham Mfg. Co., South Windham, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Written on reverse in pencil, "End of Mill at South Windham, Me." 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 26: W. H. Bacon & Co, Coat Manufactory, Standish, Cumberland Co., Maine (Box 1, Folder 3)
      William H. Bacon b.c.1844, see NARA film 1254478, p.497A for additional biographical information. Group of aproximately 25 people standing in front of coat manufactory. 17.5 x 11.5 cm.
    - Item 27: George's River Mills, Warren, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Photographed by J. Henry Allen, South Thomaston, Me. Man on horse in front of mill building. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 28: Lockwood Cotton Mills, Waterville, Me. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      n.d. Views of Waterville, Maine, published by C. G. Carleton. Railroad trestle over river with mills beyond. 17.5 x 10 cm.
  - Massachusetts (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 1: Hamilton Woolen Mill, Amesbury, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Published by Currier and Jones, Amesbury and Salisbury, Mass. Street view, mill buildings, horse drawn wagon on left. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: Smith & Dove Mfg. Co., Andover, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. View of river, Smith & Dove, town in distance. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 3: Talbot Mills, housing, No. Billerica, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Written on reverse in pencil, "House occupied by Mr. Holden and Mr. Thohlrausch." Residents posing in front of house. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: View of Bondsville, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Written on reverse in pencil, "Boston Duck Co." 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Ashworth & Jones' Mill, in the course of the flood, Cherry Valley, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      No. 4 in the series the Great Flood at Worcester, Mass., photographed and published by Edwin N. Peabody, Salem Mass. ca. 1876. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 6: Ruins of No. 1 Mill, Chicopee Falls, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      ca. 1876. Mill ruins after fire. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 7: Merchants Dye House, Dedham, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Mass. n.d. Stamp on reverse: Alden Photo Co., Boston, Mass.17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 8: Merchants Woolen Co., Dedham, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      ca. 1878-1880. Image depicts a cluster of three- and four-story buildings across a lake or pond (buildings are reflected in the water). Stamped on reverse: "Chester H. Brown." Alden Photo Co., 503 Washington St., Boston, Mass. 18 x 10 cm.
    - Item 9: Thomas Barrows Woolen Mill, Dedham, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Albumen print, ca. 1870s. Image shows a four-story building with a tower and cupola on the left. The building extends quite a way to the right. Tall bare tree in front of the building with dirt roads surrounding it. Barrow's mill was sold in 1872 to Merchants Woolen Co. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 10: Nashawannuck Mill and Office, Easthampton, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the series, Views of Easthampton, Mass. Published by F.H. Putnam & Co., photographed by Knowlton Bros. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 11: View of Fall River, Mass (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Photographed and published by Kilburn Bros., Littleton, New Hampshire. View of city in winter. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 12: Large Public Gathering, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Photographed by W. H. Cushing. Very large crowd of people seated in what appears to be a park. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 13: American Linen, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. published by Gay's Gallery of Art. Shows mill and river in the distance. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 14: American Print Works (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Fall River, MA.
    - Item 15: Chace Mills, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Published by Joseph W. Warren. Exterior side view. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 16: Granite Mill fire, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Published by Gay's Gallery of Art. Men clearing the burnt wreckage. ca. 1874. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 17: Granite Mills Fire, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Published by Gay's Gallery of Art. Fire hoses spraying water on fire damaged mill. ca. 1874. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 18: Granite Mills Fire, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Published by Gay's Gallery of Art. Exterior of fire damaged mill building. ca. 1874. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 19: Granite Mills Fire, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Published by Gay's Gallery of Art. Exterior of mill building from side. ca. 1874. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 20: Granite Mill fire, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 21: View of housing in Fall river from No. East (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Photographed and published by Joseph W. Warren. Written on front (ink) Fall River, No. 5 No. East. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 22: Mechanicsville, Fall River, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Photographed and published by Joseph W. Warren. White house on left, town in distance. Written on front in ink, "No 9 - Mechanicsville." 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 23: Glendale, from the south, Glendale Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. American Scenery, Hall, Photographer, Stockbridge, Mass. Woman looking though binoculars in foreground, river and Glendale in distance. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 24: Henry Kohlman's Oil Clothing Manufactory (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Gloucester, MA, ca. 1880.
    - Item 25: Stevens & Company card room, first breaker (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Haverhill, MA
    - Item 26: Stevens & Company card room, first breaker (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 27: City Hall, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      ca. 1870. n.d. Views of Haverhill and Vicinity, Photographed by A.W. Anderson. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 28: Eagle House, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the Series, Views of Haverhill Mass., and Vicinity. Photographed/published by G.C. Robinson. Large house festooned with flags and banners. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 29: Great Conflagration, Haverhill, Mass., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      February 17 and 18, 1882. Photographed by P. W. Tennant. View of the ruins. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 30: Stevens & Company textile fabrics (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 31: Haverhill Bridge, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      ca. 1873. Photographed by A. W. Anderson. Covered bridge. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 32: Haverhill Bridge, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Photographed/published by G.C. Robinson. Covered bridge in winter. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 33: Great Fire, Haverhill, Mass., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      From the series, "Ruins of the Great Fire," February 17 and 18, 1882. Photographed and published by A. W. Anderson. View of burned buildings along river, from Currier Block, near Depot, looking East. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 34: Great Fire, Haverhill, Mass., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      From the series, "Ruins of the Great Fire," February 17 and 18, 1882. Photographed and published by A. W. Anderson. View of smoldering and burned buildings along river, from Franklin Block, Merrimack Street, looking West 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 35: Great Fire, Haverhill, Mass., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 36: View of the Ruins of the Great Conflagration, Haverhill, Mass, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      February 17 and 18, 1882. Photographed by P. W. Tennant. Remains of multiple burned buildings along the river, railroad bridge in distance. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 37: Winter view of Water Street, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the series, "Views in Haverhill, Mass. & Vicinity." Published by G.C. Robinson. Snowy street view, multiple horse drawn sleighs pulled up along side of road. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 38: View of Merrimack Street from Water Street, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the series, "Views in Haverhill, Mass. & Vicinity." Published by G.C. Robinson. American flags suspended over street, horse drawn carriages in street. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 39: View of Merrimack Street from Washington Square, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the series, "Views in Haverhill, Mass. & Vicinity." Published by G.C. Robinson. Houses and church on left, S.D. Maynard & Co. on right. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 40: Water Street, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Horse and buggies lined up along street. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 41: Water Street, Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 42: View of Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the series, "Views in Haverhill, Mass. & Vicinity." Published by G.C. Robinson. Winter bird's eye view of Haverhill. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 43: View of Haverhill, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Published by G.C. Robinson. Bird's eye view of Haverhill. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 44: Upper Canal, Rapids, and Free Bridge from Aqueduct Archway, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. No. 8982 in the Popular Series, "American Views." Published by E. & H.T. Anthony & Co., 591 Broadway, New York, N.Y. Partial view of barge carrying stone in foreground, dam and bridge beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 45: Building Holyoke Dam (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Series G, 217, from the Series, "Holyoke and Vicinity." Photographed and published by John B.Tutcliffe. View from canal overflow, railroad tracks in foreground, construction material and partial dam beyond. 17.5 x 9.5 cm.
    - Item 46: Holyoke Dam (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. View of dam with town in distance. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 47: Dam (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. View of dam 1017 feet in length, 30 feet in height. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 48: Connecticut River Dam & Bridge, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. From the series, Stereoscopic Views, Massachusetts---Connecticut Valley. Published by Milan P.Warner. 18 x 10 cm.
    - Item 49: Aqueduct Archway and Gatehouse, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. No. 8984 in the Popular Series, "American Views." Published by E. & H.T. Anthony & Co., 591 Broadway, New York, N.Y. Looking east, South Hadley in distance, man sitting atop archway. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 50: Hadley Thread Mill, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. No. 8989 in the Popular Series, "American Views." Published by E. & H.T. Anthony & Co., 591 Broadway, New York, N.Y. Side view of Thread Mill, Paper Mill in distance, 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 51: Hadley Thread Mill, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 52: Lyman Canal and Lyman Mills, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Published by Geo. H. Ireland and Co. Canal on left and mills on right. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 53: Dwight Street, Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Dwight Street, Holyoke, Mass. n.d. From the Famous Series, "Holyoke Views." Published by F. Forest and Co. Bird's eye view of mill buildings. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 54: View of Holyoke, Mass. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      n.d. Photographed and published by A. E. Alden, A. J. Alden, artists. View of Holyoke from across river. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - Massachusetts, Lawrence: General (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Item 1: [Mill Building, Lawrence, Mass.] (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. Stamp on reverse, Geo. H. Leck, Photographer, 283 Essex St. Lawrence, Mass. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: Arlington Mill, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Item 3: Arlington Mill, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. Men standing in front of the mill building, mill in distance. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Arlington Mills, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. Trees, mill, canal. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Atlantic Cotton Mills, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Alden Photo Co., Boston, Mass. n.d. 18.5 x 10.7 cm.
    - Item 6: Atlantic Cotton Mills, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. Atlantic Cotton Mills viewed from the river. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 7: Atlantic Cotton Mills, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. From The "Best" Series, Lawrence & Vicinity. Published by Miller and Best, 67 High St., Boston, Mass. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 8: Atlantic Cotton Mills, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Item 9: Atlantic Cotton Mill, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      A.B. Hamor's New Photographic Studio (formerly Lufkin & Hamor.), Lawrence, Mass. ca. 1873. 17.6 x 8.7 cm.
    - Item 10: Biederwolf Tabernacle, Lawrence, Mass., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Written on reverse, ink: Feb. 19, 1917, view from south side of north canal. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 11: Biederwolf Tabernacle, Lawrence, Mass., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Written on reverse, ink: Feb 19, 1917, view from choir loft. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 12: Biederwolf Tabernacle, Lawrence, Mass., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Written on reverse, ink: Feb 19, 1917, rear of auditorium. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 13: Biederwolf Tabernacle, Lawrence, Mass., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Written on reverse, ink: Feb 19, 1917, rear of auditorium. 18 x 9 cm.
    - Item 14: R. R. Bridge After Fire, Lawrence, Mass., 1881 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      July, 1881. Published by A.B. Hamor, 467 Essex Street, Lawrence, Mass. Destroyed R.R. bridge, mill building in background. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 15: Ruins of Fall Bridge, Lawrence, Mass., 1881 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Noted on front: Ruins of Fall Bridge from Boston and Maine R.R. Bridge. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 16: Jail, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. Published by I.A. Whitcomb, 93 Essex St., Lawrence, Mass. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 17: Police Station, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Item 18: North Canal, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      n.d. Showing boarding houses and Atlantic Cotton Mills. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 19: North Canal from Pacific Mill chimney, Lawrence, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 1)